Eduardo Brasileiro

409 Hanson Rd • Durham, NC 27713 (919) 744-6716 • epbrasil717@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL OVERVIEW

Driven professional with experience handling critical projects and developing solutions. Strong ability to present and communicate complex topics to people of varied technical backgrounds. Direct use of analysis and visualization of large data to provide decision support to various industry representatives. Motivated and organized leader focused on meeting timelines and providing measurable results. Recipient of OneSAS Award from SAS Solutions OnDemand.

EDUCATION

NORTH CAROLINA STATE UNIVERSITY, INSTITUTE FOR ADVANCED ANALYTICS Master of Science in Analytics Raleigh, NC May 2015

- Practicum: Developed multiple econometric stress testing models on M&T Bank's residential mortgage and home equity lines of credit portfolios for the Dodd-Frank Act Stress Tests and Comprehensive Capital Analysis and Review
- Practicum Team Lead: Organized technical team and established high level project vision to accomplish goals and deliverables discussed with M&T Bank liaison

NORTH CAROLINA STATE UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Science in Applied Mathematics, summa cum laude **Bachelor of Science in Textile Engineering**, summa cum laude

Raleigh, NC December 2011 May 2011

- Valedictorian
- Minor Spanish

TECHNICAL / PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Base SAS, SAS Macro, VBA, SQL, Python, D3.js, JavaScript

Software Packages: SAS Enterprise Guide, SAS Enterprise Miner, Microsoft Office Suite,

SPSS, Tableau

Professional Development: Brody Communications Trained

Certifications: Base Programmer for SAS 9

Advanced Programmer for SAS 9
Statistical Business Analyst Using SAS 9

Predictive Modeler Using SAS Enterprise Miner 7

Google Analytics Individual Qualification

Languages: English, Portuguese, Spanish

EXPERIENCE

SAS SOLUTIONS ONDEMAND ADVANCED ANALYTICS LAB Analytical Consultant

Cary, NC

June 2015 - Present

- Received OneSAS Award for proactive approach with escalated customer
- Guided over a dozen analysts in designing and implementing healthcare fraud solution
- Developed analytic code bases to enhance fraud detection in healthcare and property insurance
- Designed and implemented visualization for cluster rules in D3.js
- Mentored and guided new analysts in learning processes and code base

Eduardo Brasileiro, Page 2

EXPERIENCE continued

GE ENERGY MANAGEMENT (CONTRACTED BY AXIEM INTERNATIONAL) Mebane, NC EngineerJuly 2013 – June 2014

- Created VBA programs to generate database documenting switchboard bill of materials
- Reported on results and managed expectations with management and designers
- Provided Microsoft Excel and VBA expertise to organize infrastructure of documentation

EPIC SYSTEMSVerona, WI **Technical Services**January 2012 – July 2013

- Provided technical solutions for emergency departments (ED) across the country
 - Led a weekly meeting overseeing billing for ED customers, ultimately becoming team expert on billing
 - Used VBA to pioneer a project to generate Key Performance Indicators database and reports
 - Managed team escalations
 - Taught Microsoft Excel macros class to groups of 20 to 30 from HR to developers
 - Communicated directly to executives as a technical coordinator
 - Communicated with customers through weekly phone calls, emails, and on-site contact
 - Used SQL to troubleshoot customer reports

NC STATE UNIVERSITY COLLEGE OF TEXTILES

Raleigh, NC

Head Tutor January 2009 – December 2011

- Tutored students in Math, Physics, Statics, Excel VBA, and Statistics courses
- Managed and organized up to 6 other tutors as the head tutor
- Developed one-on-one communication and teaching skills

CIVIC INVOLVEMENT AND VOLUNTEER

BIKE AND BUILD May 2011 – August 2011

- Raised over \$4,000 for affordable housing
- Cycled over 4,000 miles from Jacksonville, FL to Monterrey, CA
- Guided youth across the country in cycling safety demonstrations

MISSION EMANUEL

February 2009 - March 2011

- Built houses in the Dominican Republic
- Led 5 groups of summer volunteers from several parts of the United States in June 2009

AWARDS

College of Engineering Award for Citizenship and Service

April 2011

• College of Physical and Mathematical Sciences Award for Scholarly Achievement

December 2011

• College of Textiles Award for Scholarly Achievement

May 2011